SHREY PASRICHA

Student (New York University) Computer Science & Computer Engineering





WHO AM I?

Maker. Creator. Engineer. Developer. Hobbyist.

I'm passionate about creating things that make the world a better place! I am an avid learner who's always excited to explore new technologies and pick up new skills. I'm also interested in anything and everything, so I've dabbled in many topics in CS and CE. This, along with a keen interest in theoretical background, allows me to pick up experience very quickly and hit the ground running with most projects I come across, no matter the field.

Creativity Problem Solving Writing Management Salesmanship Soldering

PERSONAL STATISTICS

I'm excited about engineering technologies at the crossroads of hardware and software - solutions that make unique use of a full tech stack, from the low-level intricacies of machine code to the high level interactivity of user-facing features. Projects I've worked on that exemplify these qualities include autonomous fire fighting drones to combat blazes in remote areas, affordable medical wearables for under-served communities, and a full-body VR Tracking solution made for under \$100.

TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Expert: C, Java, JavaScript,

Proficient: C++, Rust, Kotlin, TypeScript

Competent: C#, Julia, Python, Lua, Bash

Familiar: Lisp (Emacs, Fennel), PowerShell

SOFTWARE

Expert: Git, GitHub, BitBucket, Jira

Proficient: Blender, IntelliJ

Competent: Fusion 360, KiCad, Emacs

Familiar: Visual Studio

TECHNOLOGIES

Expert: HTML/CSS, Node.js, Webpack, Fire-

oase

Proficient: PlatformIO, Arduino, Meson, CMake,

Microcontrollers (AVR, PIC, ARM), ReactJS, Unity, SteamVR,

Google Cloud Platform, Azure

Competent: WebGL/OpenGL, Three.js, Docker

Familiar: Unreal 4

SKILLS

Expert: Linux

Proficient: System Administration, LATEX

Competent: Network Configuration, CAD, 3D Printing, Sol-

dering

Familiar: Laser Cutting

PROJECTS

Personal projects I've worked on include: RC cars with custom firmware and electronics, a custom arcade stick, a linux dashboard, a variety of Minecraft mods, running a homelab server, and much more!

HOBBIES

I love creating engineering projects as a hobby! I also love listening to and producing music, DJ-ing, 3D modelling and animation, travelling, and reading science-fiction!

LANGUAGES

English - Native **Hindi** - Proficient

CAREER EXPERIENCE

2019 – 2020 Lead Engineer for Virtual Reality & Augmented Reality

TechRow

Lead and managed team of three developers to create an educational VR / AR video streaming platform. Designed and implemented front-end and back-end architecture to facilitate streaming content to both web (via A-Frame / Three.js embedded in React.js) and PC / Mobile devices (via Unity Game Engine).

JavaScript | TypeScript | React.js | Firebase & GCP | WebGL | C# | Unity

2019 Summer

Machine Learning / Al Intern

Intellect SEEC

Developed sentiment analysis classifier over the course of three weeks for use in aggregating and evaluating business review data. My program was used to analyse data from Glassdoor and extract employee sentiment for 300,000 businesses. This internship fostered my skills in Python and Machine Learning.

Python | TensorFlow | SciPy | Linux

STUDENT EXPERIENCE

2017 - 2022 Hackathon Participant, Winner, Mentor, and Judge

Various Schools and Universities

Attended 10+ hackathons and won 7 awards, such as Best Hardware Hack at Hack River Dell 2017 for a heart rate music matching app, and Best Hack for Resilience at Pennapps XX for an autonomous firefighting drone. Team leader during hackathons, fostering enthusiasm and positivity in teammates as well as managing them and integrating everyone's code. Mentored and judged at TeenHacks LI 2019 and RidgeHacks 2022, teaching and advising participants and then assessing their projects.

C++ | Arduino | PlatformIO | JavaScript | Java | Python | Julia | GCP | And More

2018 – 2019 **President**

Ridge Computer Science Club

Organised and led computer science club that held weekly meetings and attended hackathons. Taught computer science and engineering concepts to members. Led organiser team and created 'RidgeHacks', our school's first hackathon. Spearheaded club engineering projects such as a custom IOT LED display board and the RidgeHacks website.

C++ | Arduino | PlatformIO | JavaScript | HTML | CSS

2017 – 2019 **Volunteer Developer & Designer**

Legwork for Lungs

Volunteered as developer for student-run cancer charity. Created website that raised \$3,000+ in donations and managed over 500 store orders, along with backend database handling. Designed marketing materials such as stickers, shirts, and social media posts.

JavaScript | HTML | CSS | Google Cloud Platform | Wix

2013 – 2016 Robotics Student

Storming Robots

Attended weekly robotics classes and league competitions. Participated in RoboCup Junior 2015 at the state level. Developed team collaboration and mechanical, electrical, and computer engineering skills. Gained experience in creating PID and autonomous systems.

LEGO Mindstorms | VEX Robotics | Arduino | AVR | RobotC | C++

EDUCATION

2019 - Present Graduation 2024

B.S. in Computer Science & B.S in Computer Engineering

New York University

I am a rising fourth year in the Dual Degree Program at NYU between our College of Arts and Sciences and our Tandon School of Engineering. This unique combination of rigorous theoretical fundamentals and practical engineering application provides both a depth *and* breadth of experience, preparing me to tackle a wide variety of real-world engineering challenges via optimised solutions based on the most appropriate technologies.

2015 - 2019

High School Diploma

Ridge High School

I studied at Ridge High School in Basking Ridge, NJ, one of the top rated high schools in the state. Courses of particular pride and interest include Robotics, AP Computer Science, AP Physics 1 and C, and AP Calculus BC.